(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T17:37:21.528801",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
私のこと 知ってますか？
Do you know who I am?
可愛く 見えてますか？
Do I look cute?
私の歌 どうだろうな
What do you think of my singing?
うまく歌えてますか？
Can I sing it well?
衣装だとか メイクだとか
My outfit and my makeup,
可愛く 見えてますか？
Do I look cute wearing them?
振付けとか ファンサとか
My choreography and fanservice,
喜んでもらえますか？
Do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands get cold and my legs shake,
それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
Even so, I want to fight because I'm an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
And I hate being looked down on too.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't casually say "just an idol" when you haven't even seen me!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted,
イメージとか強要するな
Don't force an image on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most in this world!
プライベート 見えないから
Since my private life is invisible,
分からないと 思います
I think you wouldn't understand.
性格とか 悪い方です
My personality is rather bad,
騙しちゃって いますか？
Did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です 本気なんです
But I'm serious, I really am!
ありのままの私を 好きになって推してください
Please love the real me and support me.
それって ワガママですか？
Is that too selfish of me?
きっと可愛くない全部分かってる それでも好かれたいアイドルだから
I know I'm not cute, but I still want to be loved because I'm an idol!
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make sarcastic remarks,
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
And I hate endless excuses too.
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
Don't casually say "is that all?"
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't set limits for me on your own.
笑い者になんてするな
Don't make a laughingstock out of me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け 誇り高きアイドル
Cut through the headwinds, a proud idol!
応援がなければ活動できない
Without your support, I couldn't go on,
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
I can't live doing only what I like.
元気あげるはずが 貰ってばかりだし
I'm supposed to give you energy, but I just receive it instead,
恩返しできる日まで 待ってて
Wait for the day I can repay you!
歓声が消えても
Even if the cheers fade away,
諦められちゃっても
Even if people give up on me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
Even so, I want to keep smiling because I'm an idol!
がって スタッフさんの
Thanks to the staff,
がって いつも家族の
thanks always to my family,
がって 生きてるアイドル
I'm an idol living on...
ばかりにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me,
虐げられるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon.
アイドルなんかという言葉も
Don't you dare say "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
without even watching me.
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted,
イメージとか強制するな
don't force your image on me.
アイドルなんかという言葉は
The words "just an idol"
キミに Baby Sweet Berry Love
Baby Sweet Berry Love for you,
本当の気持ちだけ
only my true feelings.
分け合えたならいいのにな願いを叶えてよ
I wish we could share them, make my wish come true!
ジューシーにファンキーいじいじされたい
Juicy and funky, wanting to be teased,
ピュアにギッティワイ足り足りベリーな
purely getting wide, lacking berry-na!
大好きなハートも
Even my most beloved heart,
ごめんねの涙も
and my tears of "I'm sorry,"
本当は素直に見せたくて伝えたい想いと
I actually want to show you honestly and share my feelings.
裏返しの態度上手に慣れない心もよ
My attitude is upside down, and my heart still struggles.
よそって片思い胸がキュッとなる
Acting like a one-sided crush makes my chest tighten,
近い距離がもどかしいよね届けていの
and the close distance is frustrating—I want to reach you!
キミと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Baby Sweet Berry Love with you,
キトキトじゃなくてエモで真っ直ぐに見つめて空色写し出し
looking straight at you with emotion, reflecting the sky's color.
もっと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Even more, Baby Sweet Berry Love,
気付けばキミの前では笑って怒って溢れたありのままでいたいの
in front of you, I laughed, got angry, wanting to be my natural self.
だから Baby Sweet Berry Love
That's why, Baby Sweet Berry Love,
ジューシーにファンキーいじいじされたいピュアにギッティワイ足り足りベリーな
Juicy and funky, wanting to be teased, purely getting wide, lacking berry-na!
探されたハートを探してみるけれど本当は自分も奥にある
I try to search for the heart, but actually, it's deep inside myself too.
まるで寂しいのに澄ましたまよい猫こぼれた夕日にじみとしてじゃ
Just like a lonely yet aloof stray cat, spilling into the sunset's blur...
不意に優しい声はしゃぐ胸の音ドタバタとかカラフルをキュンと満ちてゆくの
Suddenly, your gentle voice makes my heart beat fast, filling up with bustling, colorful heartbeats!
キミと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Baby Sweet Berry Love with you,
中身女だけ大事であればあるほど隠してしまうの
the more precious my girlish contents are, the more I try to hide them.
だけど Baby Sweet Berry Love
But Baby Sweet Berry Love,
自分のこころまで分からないときはキミと確かめ合いたいのだから
when I don't even understand my own heart, I want to confirm it together with you.
キミと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Baby Sweet Berry Love with you,
自分を守るより大切なことがあるのこんなにも近くに
there is something more important than protecting myself, right here so close.
ジューシーにファンキー
Juicy and funky,
いじいじされたいピュアにギッティワイ足り足りベリーな
wanting to be teased, purely getting wide, lacking berry-na!
もっと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Even more, Baby Sweet Berry Love,
気付けばキミの前では笑って怒って溢れたありのままでいたい
in front of you, I laughed, got angry, wanting to be my natural self.
だから Baby Sweet Berry Love
That's why, Baby Sweet Berry Love,
こんなにも好きだよ
I love you this much!
ジューシーにファンキーいじいじされたいピュアにギッティワイ足り足りベリーな
Juicy and funky, wanting to be teased, purely getting wide, lacking berry-na!
ずっと Baby Sweet Berry Love
Forever Baby Sweet Berry Love.
伝え合った心の温度を
The warmth our hearts shared
そっと大事そうに抱え歩いていた
gently holding it close as we walked along.
答えのない願いの中で
Within unanswered wishes,
言葉は未来変えて
words can change the future.
幼い頃ずっと
Since I was little,
夢見ていた私にはまだ遠いけど
the dream I saw was still so far away,
君がいれば少しは強くなれる気がして
but with you here, I feel a little stronger.
明日の色を重ね塗った
Painting layers over tomorrow's colors,
呼んだ希望辿って止めた世界を超えた
I traced the hope and crossed the halted world.
諦めない想いいっしか心繋げた
Unwavering feelings connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Instead of crying, let's smile and greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if the vow we made hurts and we fall,
君のココロを 守るため
to protect your heart...
記憶のない時の流れにきっと求めていた
In the timeless flow of memories, I'm sure I sought
温かさはあって包まれた瞬間すべての
a warmth that embraced me in every single moment,
想いは君へ巡る
and all those feelings return to you.
空に向かって走り手にした
Running toward the sky, I grasped
いくつもの尊い光胸にしまって
countless precious lights held close to my heart,
私の中の輝きに変えて
turning them into the radiance within me.
迷いを全部放って飛ぼう
Let's cast away all doubts and fly!
正解の見えない入り組んだ迷路を抜け
Escaping the tangled maze with no clear answer,
君が流した涙で心目覚めた
my heart awoke with the tears you shed.
そして知った世界はこんなにもまだ綺麗で
And the world I came to know is still so bright,
新しい可能性を生むのだろう
giving birth to brand new possibilities.
時のカケラの願いから
From the wish of time's fragments...
救い信じて割れた想い
Believing in salvation, shattered feelings
私が始まりに立って
stand at my beginning,
君の笑顔を取り戻すよ
to bring your smile back.
真実の奇跡になって
Becoming a miracle of truth!
呼んだ希望辿って止めた世界を超えた
I traced the hope and crossed the halted world.
諦めない想いいっしか心繋げた
Unwavering feelings connected our hearts.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Instead of crying, let's smile and greet tomorrow.
決めた誓い辛くて倒れても
Even if the vow we made hurts and we fall,
君のココロを 守るため
to protect your heart...
君の側にいよう
I will be by your side.
いつの間にか見つけてた遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it,
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
scenery I couldn't see all by myself.
波打つ風の音と加速していく想いに
To rippling winds and accelerating feelings,
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt a sudden confusion.
ずっと追いかけた理想の姿はまだ届かなくて遠いけど
The ideal self I chased is still far out of reach,
きっとこの瞬間をかけがえないみんなで共に行くよ
I'll go together with everyone in this moment!
手を繋いで 3、2、1！
Holding hands, 3, 2, 1!
輝き宿して
With a sparkle in your heart,
夢の場所へ！
to the place in my dream!
駆け抜けていく
Rushing on forward,
僕たちの青春の光は
the light of our youth keeps going,
誰にも止められないよ！
no one can stop it!
笑い合う分だけ優しく
Every smile that we'll make gently,
こぼれる涙さえ
even the tears that we'll shed now,
今 ほら輝かせ 明日へ運ぶから
come on, make them shine, we're taking them all into tomorrow.
君の隣へ
To be with you,
僕たちは世界を超えて行く
we'll cross the line between our worlds,
迎えに行くよ
we'll come to get you.
まだ見えない明日も キラメキに変えてきっと
No one knows what tomorrow holds, but we can make it shine bright, I know,
僕たちが未来へと 連れて行くから！
to a bright and brilliant future we'll take you there with us!
背伸びしては手を伸ばす 憧れの
Reaching as high as I can to become a star
行き先示す星になろう
that shows you your way.
つまずくその度に手を差し伸べ合えたら
If whenever we trip and fall, we lend each other a hand,
すぐに届くはずさ
I'm sure we'll all be there in no time.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気が
To take that first step, it took a little bit of courage,
もう消えないように繋げよう
let's keep it going strong so it never fades away.
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて 共に行くよ！
Savoring even our uncertainty and anxiety as part of it all, come on, let's all go!
目を合わせて
Looking each other in the eye,
3.2.1！
3, 2, 1!
晴れ渡る希望へ 飛び出せるよ！
We can fly through the clear skies shining with our dreams!
突き抜けていく
Charging on forward,
僕たちの透き通る決意は
our clear resolve keeps going,
まだまだ止められないよ！
there's nothing that can stop it!
ありきたりな今日こそ トキメキに変えてもっと僕たちがいつまでも
Today might be another boring day, but we can fill it with excitement, and more,
背中押すから
we'll always be there for you!
ずっと一人で描いていた
That painting you've been painting by yourself,
キャンバスいつからかコライトになって
if the canvas one day is clouded with a coal black,
また少しずつ芽生える大好きを紡ぎ
you can start again slowly, weave together everything new that you love,
どこまでも高く あすいろの空へ
and fly higher than ever before into tomorrow's bright sky.
駆け抜けていく
Rushing on forward,
僕たちの青春の光は
the light of our youth keeps going,
誰にも止められないよ！
no one can stop it!
笑い合う分だけ優しく
Every smile that we'll make gently,
こぼれる涙さえ
even the tears that we'll shed now,
ほら輝かせ 明日へ運ぶから
come on, make them shine, we're taking them all into tomorrow.
君の隣へ
To be with you,
僕たちは世界を超えて行く
we'll cross the line between our worlds,
迎えに行くよ
we'll come to get you.
まだ見えない明日も キラメキに変えてきっと僕たちが
No one knows what tomorrow holds, but we can make it shine bright, I know,
未来へと
to a bright and brilliant future...
果てのない未来へと
into an endless, limitless future,
連れて行くから！
we'll take you there with us!
あやめ！あやめ！あやめ！
Ayame! Ayame! Ayame!
みんなありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you everyone! Congratulations!
ありがとうね。二人とも集まってくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you both so much for gathering here.
いやいや、本当らにね。
No, really, seriously.
可愛いよな、本当。めでたいよ。
So cute, truly. Such a happy occasion.
今回はあすいろClearSkyなんだね？
This time it's "Asuiro ClearSky," right?
なんかさ、ゆたっちはさ、だいぶ百歌繚乱花吹雪をやってきてたじゃないですか。
You've been doing "Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki" a lot recently, right?
すりまくりすりまくりですよ。
Rubbing it in everywhere!
だったので、ちょっと新しい歌を3人で歌ったことない3人でね、歌いたいなと。
So we wanted to sing a new song together as the three of us, since we haven't sung together before.
おうちであすいろClearSkyを聞いてたときに
When I was listening to "Asuiro ClearSky" at home,
これ百歌繚乱チームで歌ったら
I thought, if the Hyakka Ryouran team sang this,
え、めっちゃいいじゃんって思って。
it would be super good!
声のバランスがすごい3人は。
The balance of our three voices is amazing.
こういい感じにね 合わさるので、とても良いのではないでしょうか！
It blends together in such a nice way, so isn't it really good?!
ということでね、えらびましたー！
And so, we chose it!
わざわざありがとうございます。歌ってくれてね、ありがとね。歌ってくれてね。
Thank you so much for going out of your way. Thanks for singing it for us!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
おめでとうございまーす！またなんかね、こんな感じのまたあるのかな？
Congratulations! I wonder if there will be more things like this again?
わしゃわしゃ、３人で？
Washa washa, the three of us?
どこに？ええー？
Where? Ehhh?
なんか、え？３人で？え？なんこ？
What, eh? The three of us? Eh? How many?
なんかね、ひょっとしたらヨーロッパみたいなね、こういうリスト、スタイルよる
You know, maybe something like Europe, this kind of list... style...
こういう踊り？踊り始めじゃ、あれあれ？
This kind of dance? Starting to dance, wait, what?
なんか、また踊ったらいいよね？踊ったらいいよね。
You know, it's good if we dance again, right? It's good if we dance.
体が勝手に、体、体が勝手に、あれあれ、踊り、踊り始めちゃ、あれあれ、踊り
Our bodies just start dancing on their own, wait, wait, start dancing, wait, wait, dancing!
なんか、ねえ、楽曲がまた出せたら、いいですの？
You know, wouldn't it be nice if we could release another song?
ここ、ここ、どこ？
Here, here, where?
まあ、こう、ご期待ということでね！みなさんお楽しみくださいませ。
Well, look forward to it! Everyone, please look forward to it.
お楽しみくださいまして！お楽しみにだの！お楽しみにしてください。
Please look forward to it! Please look forward to it! Please look forward to it.
日本語難しいね。わかんない。
Japanese is hard. I don't get it.
じゃ、我々と…！見おさめとね。じゃ、うん。あ、あやめちゃんも、うん。あとも見とけようじゃん。
Well, with us...! A last look. Well, yeah. Ah, Ayame-chan too, yeah. Let's watch the rest too.
あ、じゃ、ちょっとステージのね。そうね、その装飾にちょっと。
Ah, then, to the stage decorations. That's right, to those decorations...
サイリウムも持って、行きたいと思います！
Let's bring our penlights and go!
ありがとうございます！頑張ってね！バイバイ！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Thank you very much! Do your best! Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
楽しかったねー！
That was fun!
画面越し今日も見えている
Today as well, you can see me through the screen,
いつもの変わらない笑顔を纏う
wearing that same, unchanging smile.
それは仮面か？
Is that a mask?
本当の自分を教えて
Tell me who I really am.
着飾りすまし顔じゃなく
Not with a primly dressed-up face,
呆れるほど臆病なリアル
but the ridiculously timid real.
偽りは it's all nothing
The lie is it's all nothing,
真実を open my heart
opening my heart to the truth.
君に全てを受け止めてほしい
I want you to accept everything.
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
We live in an accelerating world,
聞き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
tired of hearing voices that love to compare.
1か0かで決められた運命ならば
If our fate is decided by 1 or 0,
抗うよ 見つけるよ 僕である理由
I'll fight it, I'll find my reason for being.
カワイイだけじゃもういられない声をあげていくんだ
I can't just be cute anymore, I'll raise my voice!
憧れの自分へ迷い一杯
Full of hesitation towards my adored self,
足元見るだけで精一杯
just watching my steps takes all I have.
矛盾をしているような僕には
Can someone as contradictory as me
君にふれることはできるのかな？
ever be able to touch you?
please me, answer
かんたんり、feeling myself
It's simple, feeling myself,
君と共鳴する心のままに飛びだせ
jump out with my heart resonating with yours!
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
We live in an accelerating world,
未知の方へ 歩くことはやめない
never stopping walking toward the unknown.
1か8かの賭けだとしても構わない
It matters not if it's a bet on 1 or 8.
立ち向かい戦うよ 頂を目指すその為に
I'll face it and fight to reach the top!
それは戦力の中に
That is within our strength,
声は力に変わる
and our voices turn into power.
あたるスター もう迷うことはない
A polar star, no longer getting lost,
僕だけの道しるべ胸にきざんで
engraving my own guidepost upon my heart.
加速していく世界で生きてく僕ら
We live in an accelerating world,
聞き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
tired of hearing voices that love to compare.
1か0かで決められた運命ならば
If our fate is decided by 1 or 0,
抗うよ 見つけるよ 僕である理由
I'll fight it, I'll find my reason for being.
いつでも僕らしくありたい
I always want to be myself.
今を輝くんだ STARDUST SONG
Shining right now, Stardust Song!
カワイイだけじゃもういられない
Just being cute isn't enough anymore.
声をあげていくんだ STARDUST SONG
I'm going to raise my voice, Stardust Song!
はいはい、笑顔でいらっしゃいでしょうか。
Yes, yes, should we be smiling?
そんなわけないことすんの！ ねぇ、あやめちゃんがさ、好きって
No way we'd do that! Hey, Ayame-chan, you said you liked...
ごめんね、ごめんさい。ということで
Sorry, sorry. So, um...
すいちゃん、とわちゃん来ていただきました！ きましたー！
Sui-chan and Towa-chan came to join us! We're here!
おめでとー！すいちゃん誕生日おめでとー！ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday, Sui-chan! Thank you!
今日はですね、すいちゃんととわちゃんとおかゆでスターダストソングを踊ってたやつを一緒に聴いて
Today, I wanted to listen together with Sui-chan, Towa-chan, and Okayu to us dancing to Stardust Song...
めちゃかっこいいと思って、おかゆは別の曲で歌ってもらおうと思って
thinking it was super cool, and I wanted Okayu to sing a different song,
この二人とにね、乗っかってスターダストソング一緒に踊りたい、歌いたいって思って
and I thought I wanted to hop on with these two, dance and sing Stardust Song together!
やったー！来てくれた！ そう、本日来ていただきました！
Yay! You came! That's right, they came today!
いやでも本当に、あやめちゃんから声かけてもらえると思わなくって
But seriously, I never thought Ayame-chan would reach out to me...
思わなくて、思えなくて
I didn't think so, I couldn't believe it!
とわちゃんは？ とわちゃんはそんなこと思った？ あやめちゃんが誘ってくれると思って
And Towa-chan? Did you think that? Did you think Ayame-chan would invite you?
え、違うの！ とわはね、心臓バクバクだったの。だって初めてじゃん。
Eh, no! Towa's heart was beating so fast. Because it's the first time!
すいちゃんととわちゃんとはマジで初めてで、こう3人でやるみたいなの
With Sui-chan and Towa-chan, it's seriously the first time doing it with the three of us.
とわちゃんはね、あの、なんだっけ？丸山ね？あったけど
And Towa-chan, um, what was it? Maruyama, right? There was that, but...
でもこうやって歌うのはね、初めてだね。ねえ。
still, singing together like this is a first, right? Yeah.
めちゃ緊張したの！誘って……誘って大丈夫？
I was super nervous! Inviting... is it okay to invite?
めちゃあやめちゃんみたいなレアキャラに！
To such a rare character like Ayame-chan!
いやいや、レアキャラにね！ いやめてよ！って思って、緊張して
No no, a rare character! Don't say that! I thought, and I was so nervous...
うわあ… うわあってなって……え、違うの！
Whoa... whoa, I got like... Eh, no!
もうなんか、本当は断られるかもしれないってちょっとめっちゃハラハラドキドキしながら
I was actually super nervous and on edge thinking she might refuse me...
あ、全然、じゃあ、ちょっと悩んだけどね
Ah, not at all, well, I did hesitate a bit though!
いや、でもめっちゃ早かったよ返事！ 「出る！」うん、二人ともね、めっちゃ早かったの！
No, but the reply was super fast! "I'll do it!" Yeah, both of you replied super fast!
わあ！ ワンチャンなんか2日、3日ぐらいなんか、おかされるかなって思って、寝かされるかなって思ってたんだけど
Wow! I thought maybe for 2 or 3 days I'd be left hanging, or put on hold.
いやもう即答だった！朝起きて、「あやめちゃんから来てる！」って思って。即答でね、いいよって言ってくれて感動してたんですの。
No, it was an instant reply! I woke up and thought, "It's from Ayame-chan!" She instantly said yes, and I was so moved.
ほら、やりたがってるでしょ？ 冗談、冗談！
See, you wanted to do it, right? Just kidding, just kidding!
ということでですね、本日はもうありがとうございました、本当に。こちらこそ！ありがとうございました。
And with that, thank you so much for today, really. Same here! Thank you very much.
お時間みたいなんで。はい、失礼いたします。
It looks like our time is up. Yes, excuse us.
さようなら！頑張って！ こんな終わり方！頑張れー！
Goodbye! Do your best! What kind of ending is this! Do your best!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに 行くよ 夢見る空へ
Without letting go of our clasped hands, let's go to the sky of our dreams!
まだ星に見上げた とても小さな空 ここで出会えたのは 外れけない奇跡
The small sky where I looked up at the stars, meeting here is an unmistakable miracle.
繰り返した一歩が きらめきをつないで 星のような笑顔
Every repeated step connects our sparkles, leading to a starlike smile.
道いいた
I found the way.
Day by day みんなの声が力になる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes my strength.
Stage by stage ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Stage by stage, what each of us aims for here...
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ抱いた夢へ
Each drawing their own path, towards the dream each of us holds.
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに 一人ひとり違う
Without letting go of our clasped hands, each and every one of us...
色で描くときめき
draws excitement in our own unique colors.
振り向くことなくまっすぐに 行くよ
Without looking back, going straight ahead,
夢見る空へ
let's go to the sky of our dreams!
麗しきStylish
A stylish beauty,
文句の付けようもないわ
with no room for complaints.
極上のSmiling つぶらな瞳は罪かな
Supreme smiling, are these round eyes a crime?
ドジな場面だって ウルルと交わしたら
Even in clumsy moments, if I tear up and exchange looks,
誰もがイチコロで許したくなっちゃう
everyone falls for me instantly and wants to forgive me—
私の美徳
that's my virtue!
誇らしきMy life
A proud life,
いつもポジティブがポリシー
always keeping positivity as my policy.
誰よりもしっかり 恵まれたこの才能で
More mindful than anyone, with this blessed talent,
余裕の毎日を 過ごすそのついでに
spending days with ease, and along the way,
悪い奴をかたづけていく私は おちゃめなヒロイン
cleaning up the bad guys, I'm a playful heroine!
#KUJIKENAIKARA! My heart
#Never give up! My heart,
明日へと突き進んで行く
pressing forward toward tomorrow.
KUJIKENAIKARA! My heart 胸が希望で溢れる
Never give up! My heart, my chest overflows with hope.
譲れない 流さない 終われぬ夢へと
Toward unyielding, unflowing, endless dreams,
狙い定めればきっと Peace of mind,to be
if I take aim, surely peace of mind, to be.
香しきDelicious
Fragrant and delicious,
美しい程の食欲
an appetite of stunning proportions.
The greatest Diamond 愛よりお金が現実
The greatest diamond, reality is money over love.
美少女だからって 擦り寄ってきたなら
If you come cozying up just because I'm a bishoujo,
戴くのは私の方、覚悟して
I'll be the one taking from you, so be prepared!
逃がしてあげない
I won't let you escape.
#KUJIKENAIKARA! My heart
Never give up! My heart,
何処へでも突き進んで行く
pressing forward anywhere.
KUJIKENAIKARA! My heart この身を捧げたくなるの
Never give up! My heart, makes me want to offer my whole self.
わーい！ あやめ先輩！
Yay! Ayame-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday to you!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
ちょっと待って何処になっちゃってんですか？
Wait, what age are you turning now?
あ、うちは、えっと1500、4、5歳ぐらいになりました！
Ah, as for me, um, I became about 1,504 or 5 years old!
おばあちゃーん！
Granny!
おばあちゃん！
す、すす、しないの！
D-d-don't say that!
いやでもダンス頑張ったね！ね！
But you worked hard on the dancing! Right?
みんなで揃えてね、こうやって、夢見る空へってね。
Everyone matched it, like this, "To the sky of dreams."
なんかこれ、あれなんだよね、マリンと、うちはブルームで、そう一緒なんだよね。
You know, for this, Marine and I are in Bloom, we're together in that.
だから団長だけやったことなくて、ちょっと心配だったんだけど、なんとね、今回この2人が先生になってくれて、教えてくれたんですよ。
So Leader had never done it, and she was a bit worried, but amazingly, these two became teachers and taught me.
はい！高速ステップ、高速ステップ、高速ステップ行って…
Yes! High-speed step, high-speed step, high-speed step...
ちなみにここ、3回ぐらい間違えました！
By the way, here we messed up about three times!
間違えたけどでも、ね、綺麗に形になりましたと、ね、よかったね！よかった！よかったですね。
We messed up, but still, it ended up taking a clean shape, right? I'm glad! Glad it worked out.
そう、よかったし、あとここがもうピタッと、そう、綺麗にね、綺麗にね、よかった、よかったねって話をしてましたね。
Yeah, I'm glad, and also right here it was so crisp, yeah, we were talking about how nice and neat it turned out.
いっぱいスクショして、ハッシュタグでつぶやいたぞ！
Take lots of screenshots and tweet them with the hashtag!
いや、そう、あやめ先輩誕生日ということでさ、もうちょっと誕生日プレゼントじゃないんですけど…
Yeah, well, since it's Ayame-senpai's birthday, not quite a birthday present, but...
団長やっぱあやめ先輩今回、ちょっとダンスとか、こう教えてくれたりとか、あとま、およばれでさ、してくださったんで、はい！
Leader, since Ayame-senpai taught us some dance stuff this time, and also invited us over, yes!
え、ちなみに、あやめ先輩、サンタさんは、信じてますか？
Eh, by the way, Ayame-senpai, do you believe in Santa Claus?
え、そらサンタさんいるよ！
Eh, Sora-Santa is real!
そうですよね！そらいるんですよ！
That's right! Sora is real!
団長、あやめ先輩のために、なんと！サンタさんを呼んできました！やったー！サンタさん、やったー！
Leader, for Ayame-senpai, amazingly! We called Santa Claus! Yay! Santa, yay!
メリークリスマス！
Merry Christmas!
あやめちゃん、メリークリスマス、サンタさんじゃあよ…
Ayame-chan, Merry Christmas, Santa-san is...
え、これサンタさん？サンタさんで、あ、サンタさんだ！
Eh, is this Santa? It's Santa, ah, it's Santa!
サンタさん！メリークリスマス！よいしょ、よいしょ、ニコニコ、ニコニコ、ニコニコ！
Santa! Merry Christmas! Heave-ho, heave-ho, smile, smile, smile!
We wish you a Merry Christmas...
adrenaline!!
単純な言葉重ねていく
Simple words keep piling up,
もっと心は素直で
wanting my heart to be more honest.
なんでもないようなその笑顔が
That seemingly insignificant smile
明日を照らす光に
becomes the light that illuminates tomorrow.
ずっと気づいていたんだって
I'd realized it all along,
この手に抱えていたんだって
I'd been holding it in my hands all along.
弾けた声に流した答えが 今
The answer carried in my bursting voice, now
そっと きっと 願い込めた
softly, surely, imbued with a wish.
ずっと まわる まわる 夢の中で
Always spinning, spinning in a dream,
繰り返し 君 と 踊った
I danced with you over and over.
揺れる 景色 道 は 続く
The swaying scenery and road continue,
通り過ぎる 風 に ふ かれ
buffeted by the passing wind.
何度も 越え て 行ける から 境界線 雲 かき分け 手 を 伸ばした
No matter how many times I can cross them—pushing aside the clouds at the border line, I reached out my hand!
涙 は 今 浮かぶ 空 に 預け て 走り出す の
Tears, now entrusted to the floating sky, as I start to run!
並んで 見つけた 輝く 光 を 手 に
Holding the shining light we found side by side in my hands!
問題 は いつも 自分 次第 さあ 未来 を 選んで
Troubles are always up to yourself, come on, choose your future!
こんがらがっ た 糸 ほど いたら 思いのまま 進もうよ
Untangle the tangled thread and let's move forward as you wish!
毎日 冒険 なんだって
Every day is an adventure, they say;
奇跡 は 無限大 なんだって
miracles are infinite, they say.
高鳴る 想い 羅針盤 の ように 今 そっと きっと 導いてく
Like a compass for my throbbing feelings, now softly, surely, it guides me onward!
そうさ 巡る 巡る 波 に 乗っかっ て
That's right, riding on the spinning, spinning waves,
風 まかせ 君 と 笑った
laughing with you, leaving it to the wind.
予想 外 は 想定 内 間違い や 失敗 も 楽しんで
The unexpected is within expectations; enjoying mistakes and failures too,
一歩 踏み出したら 見えた 可能性 行き止まり の 壁 壊して
when I took a step forward, possibilities appeared—breaking down the dead-end walls!
まだ 知らない 世界 君 と 一緒 なら 怖くない よ
If I'm with you in a world I don't know yet, I'm not afraid!
わくわく している 今 が 一番 大好き
I love right now the most, feeling so excited!
ゆっくり 焦んない 自分のペースで行こう
Go at your own pace, slowly, without rushing;
大丈夫 心配ない 描いたもの全部叶えるよ
it's alright, no worries, all your painted dreams will come true!
ずっと まわる まわる 夢の中で
Always spinning, spinning in a dream,
繰り返し 君 と 踊った
I danced with you over and over.
いつか 君 と 約束 した 願い の 架け橋 を 渡って
Crossing the bridge of wishes I promised you someday,
何度も 越え て 行ける から 境界線 雲 かき分け 手 を 伸ばした
no matter how many times I can cross them—pushing aside the clouds at the border line, I reached out my hand!
涙 は 今 浮かぶ 空 に 預け て 走り出す の
Tears, now entrusted to the floating sky, as I start to run!
並んで 見つけた 輝く 光 を 手 に
Holding the shining light we found side by side in my hands!
わくわく している 今 が 一番 大好き
I love right now the most, feeling so excited!
あやめちゃーん！
Ayame-chaan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとー！ありがとうー！
Thank you! Thank you!
ねえ、前回も来てくれたのに今回も来てくれてありがとうございます！
Hey, thank you so much for coming last time and coming again this time!
ありがとうございます！来てくれてめっちゃ嬉しいよー！
Thank you so much! We're so happy you came!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
なんかね、前回はさ、なんかこう、ヨガのおかゆと、でヨガのころねとって、それぞれで踊ったんだけど、今回はおかころの二人と一緒に歌って踊りたくて
You know, last time, Okayu danced to yoga, and Korone danced to yoga separately, but this time I wanted to sing and dance together with the two of them, Okakoro!
おおお！で、何歌おうかって考えたときに、
Ooh! And when we thought about what to sing...
どこかに歌ってほしい曲がね、あの、ベースに考えていたんですけど、
There was a song I really wanted everyone to sing,
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
そうなの。で、それを決めた時に、
That's right. And when I decided on that,
この2人の低音な感じに歌ってほしいと思ったのね。
I thought it'd be great if these two could sing it with a low-pitched vibe.
で、そこに、あわよくばよもちょっと添えられたらなみたいな、あの、そう。
And, you know, if possible, have Yomo added to it, something like that—yeah.
いやいやいや、主役だからね。そう。本当だよ。
No, no, no, you're the star! That's right, seriously.
あくまでも2人を基準に選んだ曲なんですけれども。
Even though I chose the song based on those two...
え、そうなの？
Huh, is that so?
なのに、一生懸命みんなわちゃわちゃ踊ってくれてありがとうございます。
Even so, thank you so much for dancing around so energetically.
いやいや、どういたしまして。
No, no, you're very welcome.
え、すごいでもこの3人に合ったよね。
It really suited these three, right?
ね、なんだかんだ初、初めてだよね、この3人。
Yeah, somehow it's the first time for these three.
初めて。そう、めっちゃレアなんだよね。レアなんだよね。
First time. Yeah, it's super rare.
いや、めっちゃ低音格好いいよね。低音な曲。
Man, low pitch is cool. A low-pitched song.
あ、低音格好いい。低音、低音、低音だって。
Ah, low pitch is cool. Low pitch, low pitch.
あ、低音、低音、低音ってね。低音、低音だって。
Ah, low pitch, right. Low pitch, low pitch.
まあ、そうかね。こういう限りでしょうね、この。
Well, that's true. Probably only this once, right, this...
え？こういう限りなのか、この組み合わせは。
Huh? Is it only for tonight, this combination?
え、今日で終わりってこと？え？
Eh, does that mean it ends today? Huh?
うん、今日限りじゃない、レアだから。
Yeah, isn't it just for tonight? Because it's rare.
なるほどね。
I see.
だからこその良さがあるってことか。そうなの、そうなの。
So that's why there's a unique appeal to it. Exactly.
え、これでこれきり、な、ないってこと？え？ないってことだね。
Eh, does that mean it won't happen ever again? It means it won't.
やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい。
Oh no, oh no, oh no, oh no.
やばい、やばい、やばい、どうしよう、どうしよう、どうしよう、どうしよう。
Oh no, what should we do, what should we do?
ま、そうかね。そっとしといたげようね。
Well, that's true. Let's just leave them be, then.
このふざけた腕が 樅の陽で 鍵をうさく鳴らす
These absurd arms ring the keys lazily in the sunlight.
隙間から見つめる月夜に
In the moonlit night peered at through the gaps,
したたる血がぱっと飛び散るような
like dripping blood scattering in a flash,
したたかで狂った逃げ方で 逃げてた
fleeing in a cunning and maddened way.
負け続けることに意味はない
There's no meaning in continuing to lose.
追っ手のその目に迷いはない
There's no hesitation in the pursuer's eyes.
無価値なぼくらと呼ぶくせに
Even though you call us valueless,
血眼で求めている
you desperately seek us out with bloodshot eyes.
したたる血がパターンで輝き
The dripping blood shines in a pattern,
教えている ぼくたちの場所を
telling us where we belong.
重力が消し飛んだ死の砂漠で きみに触れたよ
In the desert of death where gravity vanished, I touched you.
ぼくらの引力だけが引き合える 傷つけ合える
Only our gravity can draw us together, can hurt one another.
輝く血で濡れた砂で なにも見えないほどの光で
On sand soaked in shining blood, in a light so bright nothing else can be seen...
ぼく以外には捕らえない いびつな姿
a distorted form that no one else can capture.
真実も現実に見せかけて 見失ってた
Truth disguised as reality was lost from sight.
話しが胸に起き唯一の言葉条理持って 世界に寄り添っていこう
Let's snuggle up to the world, holding only the words born in our chests.
世界はひとつでもないし
The world isn't just one,
溶け切れない煩悩は 溜まって
and unresolvable worldly desires pile up,
欲しがって 消える前に現れるの
craving before they vanish.
端正な 日々の予定
The simple schedule of days—
どいつもこいつでも常識のあなただって きっと感じて
no matter who it is, even your conventional self surely feels it.
それも別に悪くないから
And that's not necessarily a bad thing.
溶け切れない煩悩は 溜まって
Unresolvable worldly desires pile up,
欲しがって 消える前に現れるの
craving before they vanish.
単純だ 日々の予定
The simple schedule of days,
どう一期で呆気なく 台無しに 倒れ出す
how absurdly and frail it collapses in a single lifetime.
ゆっくり 止まった先には
In the silence where time finally stopped,
不思議合いなほど 綺麗に ぴったり 相合があった
there was a fit so bizarrely neat.
ただ 終わらない夢の中 戻ってなんていられない
I can't just stay back in an endless dream.
目覚め 傷だらけになって 痛いって
Awakening covered in scars, hurting,
痛いって いま 人から借りてきた 言葉あてに 進まないで
hurting, now—don't advance using borrowed words,
胸響かせないで
don't let your chest echo with them.
結局は 自分次第に
In the end, it's all up to oneself.
一体は何が嘘で
What on earth is a lie,
何が本当か
and what is the truth?
ほら 混ざり合い 不揃いな 葛藤の中 疑って
Look, doubting amidst intertwined, ragged conflicts,
真実も 現実に見せかけて 見失ってた
truth disguised as reality was lost from sight.
話しが 胸に起き唯一の言葉 条件持って 世界に 寄り添っていこう
Let's snuggle up to the world, holding the unique words born in our chests.
世界は一つでもないし
The world isn't just one, either.
ほら 混ざり合い 不揃いな 葛藤の中 疑って
Look, doubting amidst intertwined, ragged conflicts,
真実も 現実に見せかけて 見失ってた
truth disguised as reality was lost from sight.
話しが 胸に起き唯一の言葉 条件持って 世界に 寄り添っていこう
Let's snuggle up to the world, holding the unique words born in our chests.
世界は一つでもないし
The world isn't just one, either.
永く凍てついた手 何も感じない
This hand has been frozen for so long, feeling nothing...
せめて 誰か 此処に気付いて
I wish at least someone would notice me here.
結局は自分次第に
Ultimately, it's all up to oneself.
巡り続ける鼓動
The beating pulse goes on and on.
tell me the meaning of the code
take me to the end of the world
巡り続ける鼓動
The beating pulse goes on and on.
はーい！
Hi-i!
おー！
Oh!
ということで！
And so...
あやあや、お、楽しかったね、あやあや！
Ayayaya! Oh, it was so fun, Ayayaya!
そうそう、もう最高だったね、あやあや！
Yeah, yeah, it was the absolute best, Ayayaya!
いやもう、私たち息ぴったりだったぞ！
Man, our breathing was totally in sync!
そう、そうだな、もうこんなんでやっちゃってさ！
Yeah, yeah, we did it like this!
ということで、
And so,
今日はかなたちゃんに、あ、すいません。
today Kanata-chan... ah, excuse me.
今日はかなたちゃんに来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Today we invited Kanata-chan to join us! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
あ、終わったんですけどね。
Ah, though the song is already over.
終わりましたね。
It's over, haha.
今日ね、あの歌ってもらった「clever」って曲なんですけど、
Today, you know, the song we had you sing called "clever,"
がが大好き、かなたさんの曲なんですけど、
It's Kanata-chan's favorite song...
すごい素敵なんだよね。でも、かなたもさ、clever好きじゃん、たぶん。
It's so wonderful, right? But Kanata, you like "clever" too, right?
好き！好き！好きなんだろうなぁっていう。
I love it! I figured you'd love it!
思ってて、で、しかも「clever」って曲ちょっとかっこいいじゃん。
And I thought, plus the song "clever" is kind of cool, right?
で、なんかかっこいい歌を一緒にかなたちゃんと歌いたいなって思ってて、
And I thought I really want to sing a cool song together with Kanata-chan,
で、「clever」を聞いたときに「これ、かなたちゃんしかいない」と思ったの。
and when I heard "clever," I thought, "This has got to be Kanata-chan!"
やばい、やばい、やばい！
No way, no way, no way!
で、おかなたちゃんに一緒、一緒に歌ってこれまでの歌ってっていう、あれを送ったんだけど。
So I sent you a message asking to sing this together.
いやもう本当にね、大喜び！心、喜びすぎて急に心の距離縮めちゃうね。
I was honestly overjoyed! I was so overjoyed my heart suddenly closed the distance!
距離縮めてもらいました。すごい頑張って。
You closed the distance right up. You worked so hard.
今日はね、もう本当に嬉しい。
Today I'm just so happy.
あやめ先輩のね、歌も声も大好きっていうのが、
Loving Ayame-senpai's singing and voice so much,
本当に、で、デビューする前に、ころねみんなに挨拶する前に行ったときにも、
honestly, even before I debuted, when I went to greet everyone...
そうだね、その時も優しくしてくれて、すごい持ち上げてくれてね。
That's right, you were so kind back then, and lifted me up so much.
いや持ち上げてない、持ち上げてない、本当事実！事実をね、もう事実陳列罪したんです。
No, I didn't lift you up, it's just the plain truth! I just stated the facts.
そしたらね、もうそれからなので、本当に一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです！ありがとう！
And ever since then, I've been so, so happy to be able to sing together with you! Thank you!
こちらこそ、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much as well!
これからも、なんか歌ってみたとか、一緒に、なんかす るコラボとかもね！
And from now on, maybe we can do cover songs or collaborations together!
あ、またね、今度も、なんかイベントが、ちょっと？
Ah, and also next time, maybe some kind of event...
あるのかな？みたいなの、ちょっと一緒に、なんかするかもみたいなもあるね！お楽しみください！
might happen? Something like that, maybe we'll do something together! Look forward to it!
ということで、かなたちゃんでした！ありがとうございました！
And with that, it was Kanata-chan! Thank you very much!
ありがとうねー！
Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に 顔をしかめたのは
The wind blowing into the boring window made me frown,
照れくささの裏返し
a sign of my bashful shyness.
曖昧にうなずく手のひらの今日
Nodding vaguely at today in my palm,
描いてる自分は少し大げさで 何か変わりそうな気がしているよ
the self I'm imagining is a bit exaggerated, feeling like something is about to change.
心に呼びかける君のせいだね 曇り空のぞいた予感
It's all because of you calling out to my heart, a premonition peeking through the cloudy sky.
手を伸ばそういつよりも力強い勇気で
Let's reach out our hands with courage stronger than ever.
光も影もまだ遠くて それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
Light and shadow are still far away, yet we want to know the reason for kindness.
今は誰の名前でもない輝きの彼方へ
Towards a radiant place beyond any name,
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
let's go find it before everything becomes the past.
この世界はまるで頼ないねと うそぶく私の目をからかうように
As if mocking my eyes doubting that this world is so unreliable,
君が見てる空は何色だろう きっと青く高く清らかいはず
what color is the sky you see? It must be blue, high, and clear.
すれ違い近づくなら いついつの日か戸惑いも受け止められていけたら
If we draw closer while passing each other, one day we'll be able to accept our hesitation.
言葉のままじゃもどかしくてだから 何度でも不器用に重ねてしまうね
Words alone are so frustrating, so time and time again we awkwardly pile them up.
喜びも悲しみもここで意味が生まれる 二人気づきはじめるその理由も
Joy and sadness find their meaning right here, and the two of us are starting to notice that reason.
声にならない切なさごと この想い、君に届け
Along with this pain I cannot put into words, these feelings, reach out to you.
光も影もまだ遠くて それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
Light and shadow are still far away, yet we want to know the reason for kindness.
今は誰の名前でもない輝きの彼方へ 全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
Towards a radiant place beyond any name, let's go find it before everything becomes the past.
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に
The wind blowing in through the boring window
顔をしかめたのは照れくささの裏返し
I grimaced as another way of showing my embarrassment,
曖昧にうなずく手のひらの今日
nodding faintly at today in the palm of my hand.
描いてる自分は少し大げさで 何か変わりそうな気がしているよ
I've depicted myself with a bit of embellishment, feeling like something is going to change.
きっと青く高くきよらかなはず
I'm sure it's blue, high, and clear.
すれ違い 近づきながら
While passing by and getting close to each other,
いつの一日 迷いも受け止めていけたら
if I could accept the confusion of every day...
言葉のままじゃもどかしくて だから何度でも
I'm impatient with expressing myself through words, so I'll awkwardly
不器用に重ねてしまうね
repeat them again and again.
喜びも悲しみもここで意味が生まれること
We've started to realize the reason why meaning is born here
二人気づき始めてるその理由を
from our shared joy and sorrow.
言葉のままじゃもどかしくて 何度でも
I'm impatient with expressing myself through words, so again and again
不器用に重ねてしまうよ
I'll awkwardly repeat them.
声にならないせつなさごと
May all of my unvoiced pain
この思い 君に届け
and my feelings reach you.
光も影もまだ遠くて それでも僕らは
Both light and shadows remain far away; nevertheless, we still
優しさの理由が知りたい
want to know the reason for kindness.
今は誰の名前でもない 輝きの彼方へ
Heading toward the shining yonder that isn't named after anyone,
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
let's go find it before everything becomes the past.
君が過去になる前に見つけるから
Because I'll find it before you become the past.
はーい、みんな！みんな！
Hii, everyone! Everyone!
今楽しんでますか？お待たせしました。
Are you enjoying it? Thanks for waiting.
えっとね、たくさんあの、もうぶっ飛ばして歌って踊ったわけですけれども、皆さん楽しんでいただけてますでしょうか？
Um, I sang and danced my heart out. I hope you all enjoyed it!
今回はね、前回と違って少しだけダンスも成長したんじゃないかなってちょっと思うんですけど、前回もねなんか成長したなって思ったんだけど、
This time, unlike last time, I feel like my dancing improved just a little bit. Well, I thought I improved last time too, but...
今回もちょっとろく成長したかなって思ってんだけど、どうですか皆さん？
I think I improved even more this time. What do you guys think?
うんうんうん、みんな褒めてくれてる！多分！多分褒めてくれてるはずです！
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Everyone's praising me! Probably! You guys must be praising me!
ということで、あの、なんかステージ立つのも少し、なんか今までのはねもうなんか恥ずかしくて、
So, um, standing on stage used to make me feel so embarrassed and...
もうなんかの全然、もう世に動けなかったんですけど、なんか、なんか自信がね、少しだけついてきて、ダンスを踊るなんか回数も多くなってきたからちょっとね自信がついたんですけれども。
I couldn't move properly at all. But recently, I've gained a bit of confidence, and since I've been dancing more often, I feel a bit more confident. However...
まあね、そんな成長した姿をみんなに少しでも、見せられたらいいなって思ってます！
Well, I hope I can show everyone even a little bit of that growth!
ということで、うれしいお知らせをここで二つ挟んでいきたいと思います。え？二つ？二つ？
With that said, I'd like to share two happy announcements here. Huh? Two? Two?
じゃ、まじで1つ目から発表していきたいと思いますよ！じゃあ、いきますよ！いいですか？心の準備は。
Well, I'll announce the first one! Okay, here we go! Are you ready? Is your heart ready?
百鬼あやめ 誕生日記念グッズ発売しまーす！やったー！
Nakiri Ayame's birthday commemorative merchandise is now on sale! Yay!
今年もやってまいりましたよ！気になるね、誕生日のフルセットはこちらです！ドドン！
It's that time of the year again! If you're curious, here is the full birthday set! Ta-da!
あ、ちょっとすみませんね。はい、あ、逆ですね、すみません！
Ah, sorry about that. Yes, wait, that's backwards, sorry!
はい、えー、1つ目は、え、ブランケット！そしてそして、おっぱいマウスパッド！お！
Yes, um, first is a blanket! And then, a boob mousepad! Oh!
そして、記念ボイス！そしてそして、特典ポストカードとなっておりまーす！やったー！すごい！
And a commemorative voice pack! And finally, a bonus postcard! Yay! Amazing!
もうもりだくさんですよ、今回も！
There's so much content this time too!
今回の記念ボイスはですね、誕生日記念「水族館デートボイス」となっておりまーす！
As for this commemorative voice pack, it's a birthday special "Aquarium Date Voice"!
あやめがね、水族館好きなので、ちょっとボイス掘り切って、掘り切って頑張っちゃいましたよ！
Since I love aquariums, I really put my all into recording this voice pack!
あのですね、ボイスはもちろん、あの、単体でも購入可能ですので、はい。
And of course, the voice pack is also available for individual purchase.
ボイスだけ欲しいなって方はね、ぜひあの水族館デートを楽しんでいただいてもろて！
So if you just want the voice, please enjoy the aquarium date!
フルセットの、よの、直筆サインが入ってきまーす！やったー！
The full set includes a hand-signed postcard! Yay!
なんかあの、小耳に挟んだんですけど
I heard through the grapevine—
なんか前回、あの、めちゃくちゃ爆速で売れましたよっていう、まねちゃん情報があったんですけど
well, I got word from Mane-chan that last time, it sold out super fast,
今回はね、どうなることやらって感じですけど。
but I wonder how it'll go this time.
このね、ポストカードは、あの、ワサビ先生の描き下ろしとなっております。
This postcard is newly illustrated by Wasabi-sensei.
ありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃかわいいよ。
Thank you so much! It's super, super cute.
そして、もちろんね、こちらグッズ単体も購入可能ですので、ぜひ皆さんゲットしてください。
And of course, you can buy these goods individually too, so please be sure to get them.
もう「よのボイス要らないです」って方ね、はい、ちょっと、ちょっと悲しいですけど。
For those of you saying, "I don't need Ayame's voice,"
ちょっと悲しいんですけどね、あのグッズでも、グッズだけでもね、ぜひ手に入れていただけたらと思います。
It's a little sad, but I hope you'll at least get the goods by themselves!
ブランケットも、ワサビ先生の描き下ろしなので、ぜひ手に入れてください。
The blanket is also newly illustrated by Wasabi-sensei, so please get it.
このブランケットもね、よが、なんか、ちょっと柔らかい素材にしてくださいって言って、
I asked for the blanket to be made of a really soft material,
あ、ちょっと硬い素材はいやだ！いやです！って言ってね、
saying, "Ah, I don't want a hard material! No way!"
ちょっとあの、ふぁわふぁわな生地になっておりますので、ぜひ皆さん、あの、ブランケットかけてね、あったかくしてください。
so it's a nice, fluffy fabric. Please use the blanket to stay warm!
おっぱいマウスパッドですね、いもち先生の描き下ろしとなっております。
Next is the oppai mousepad, illustrated by Imochi-sensei.
ありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃかわいいよ。
Thank you so much! It's super cute.
なんかちょっと、なんかいつも、いつもよりセ、セクシーな感じのようですけれども。
It looks a little more sexy than usual, though!
はい、ぜひ皆さんおうちに置いてください。
Yes, please display it in your room, everyone.
ということで、も、あの1つの、おし、おしらせをここで終了なんですけれども。
With that, that concludes this announcement here...
ま、気になるあと一個ですね！
Now, for the one final thing you're curious about!
え？
Huh?
なんでしょう？
What could it be?
前回は？前回のは？10周年記念では？
What about last time? In our 10th-anniversary stream...
最後に何を発表しましたか、皆さん？
What did we announce at the very end, everyone?
そうです！オリジナルソングを発表させていただきましたね。
That's right! We announced an original song.
前回は。
Last time.
今回も！オリジナルソングが、ありまーーす！やったー！よっしゃー！
This time too, there is an original song! Yay! Woohoo!
ということで、あの今回もね、オリジナル曲用意しております！もうずっとずっと準備してね、あの歌って練習してきたので、おだ、踊りもね、めちゃくちゃ練習してきたので、もうぜひ見てください！
So we've prepared an original song this time too! I've been practicing singing and dancing for a long time, so please check it out!
じゃ、ちょっとね、お色直ししてきますので、皆しゃん、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと待っててね！ばいばーい！
Well then, I'm going to go change my outfit, so everyone, please wait just a little bit! Bye-bye!
鈴の音響く 深い夜とお月様
The bell's chime echoes into the deep night and the moon
今宵 宴の用意を高笑い こらえ
Tonight, suppressing my chuckles as I prepare the feast
噯気、式神を連れ立って 戯れに興じるの
Belching and summoning my shikigami, reveling in play
流れ行く時を想う 消え行く日々ならば
Thinking of passing time, if these days are fading away
この刹那さえ美しくしよう 咲かせて空高く
Let's make even this fleeting moment beautiful, blooming high in the sky
はんなり はんなり 夢花火 ふんわり ふんわり 願うのは
Gracefully, gracefully, dream fireworks, gently, gently, what I wish for
現世の思い出だけ ずっと
is just the memories of this mortal world, forever
幾年時を重ねて 巡り会う世は情け
Piling up years, the world we meet in again is full of grace
とこしへに余は 歌って笑っていたいのだ
Eternally, I want to sing and laugh on
静寂満ちる 浮かぶ三つ影法師
Filled with silence, three floating silhouettes
今宵 祭りのお後を 寂しさ抑え
Tonight, suppressing the loneliness after the festival ends
噯気、皆どもを想いながら まどろみへ委ねるの
Belching, thinking of everyone as I surrender to slumber
生まれては弾き消える 泡沫の調べは
Born only to burst and fade, the bubble's melody
その一瞬も大切にしよう 聞かせて鮮やかに
Let's cherish even that single instant, let me hear it vividly
きんらり きんらり 夢花火 ひそり ひそり 祈るのは
Glitteringly, glitteringly, dream fireworks, quietly, quietly, what I pray for
永遠の楽しさだけ ずっと
is just eternal joy, forever
幾年時を重ねて 思い出す余はあわれ
Piling up years, I look pitiful remembering it
こころゆくまで 踊って騒いでいたいのさ
I want to dance and make merry to my heart's content
移りゆく 時の中で
Amidst the shifting times,
宿る気もさらば
if even lingering spirits depart,
この働きも 色どりとなれ
may this labor too become colorful,
高めて 鮮やかに
elevating them vividly
港と
towards the port...
そっと
Gently,
はんなり はんなり 夢花火
soft and graceful, a dream fireworks show.
ふわり ふわり 祈るのは
Floating and drifting, what I pray for
現世の 楽しいことだけ
is only the joyful memories of this world,
いつまでも
forever and ever.
幾年 時を重ねて 巡り会う世は情け
Through the accumulation of years, encounters in this world are tender,
忘れないように
so that we won't forget them.
とこしへにようは
For eternity...
港笑っていたいのよだん
I want to keep smiling at the port.